<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>


<resources>

    <!-- TODO should put these text blocks into strings.xml  -->

    <!-- main content of the learning cards, for heading, check the array below  -->
    <!-- make sure to match the main content of the card with the heading -->
    <!--also make sure that badENumbersCardArray and headingForBadENumbersArray have the same number of entries
     or you'll get an arrayOutOfBounds exception -->
    <!--maybe you could reference these values from some strings.xml file so it would be more readable
    and easier for translation -->

    <string-array name="badENumbersCardArray">

        <!--colors -->

        <item>E129 May have slightly less allergy/intolerance reaction by aspirin intolerant people and
            asthmatics than most of the azo dyes, although those with skin sensitivities should be
            careful. Allura red has also been connected with cancer in mice.
        </item>


        <item>Otherwise known as MSG, Monosodium Glutamate, E621 is a flavour enhancer that’s
            commonly used to pep up food products and make them taste better. Unfortunately,
            it is known to cause problems for some people – and certain people seem to more sensitive
            to its effects than others. Amongst the known side effects, MSG can cause symptoms such
            as headaches, nausea, dizziness, muscle pain, palpitations and even pain.</item>


        <item>Aspartame, E951 is an artificial sweetener that’s commonly used as a sweetening ingredient.
            In particular, it’s often found in products aimed at dieters or diabetics, such as desserts,
            low-fat foods, low sugar drinks, snacks and sweets. It’s well known to be linked to problems
            in people who suffer from the condition PKU, and they are well advised to avoid it completely.
            But aspartame has become a concern to other people too and side effects, such as headaches,
            have often been reported.</item>

        <item>E211, sodium benzoate, is an E number that’s used as a preservative and is found in products
            such as margarine, salad dressing, soy sauce, sweets and soft drinks. Studies have found
            that it’s linked to hyperactivity in children, plus it may cause reactions in people have
            allergic conditions or asthma.</item>

        <item>E150d - Class IV caramel. It is mostly used in  products that has brown to black colour.
            Soluble in water and with a specific, sometimes bitter, taste.Side effects are manifested
            from the use of E150c and E150d, where intestinal problems may occur. Potentially CARCINOGENIC.
            Due to the complex nature of the mixtures, toxicology tests are still being carried out.</item>

        <item>E150c Ammonia caramel - <b>Class IV</b> caramel. It is mostly used in  products that has brown to black colour.
            Soluble in water and with a specific, sometimes bitter, taste.Side effects are manifested
            from the use of E150c and E150d, where intestinal problems may occur. Potentially CARCINOGENIC.
            Due to the complex nature of the mixtures, toxicology tests are still being carried out.</item>


        <item>E151 – brilliant black BN, E151 is a form of black synthetic dye that is used as a food
            colouring in some products. However, concerns have been raised in other countries,
            as it’s been linked to allergic reactions in some people. It is already banned in Australia,
            Austria, America, Germany, Norway, Sweden, Switzerland, Belgium and France.</item>

        <item>E133 – brilliant blue FCF, is another synthetic blue colouring dye, which adds a blue
            colour to some products. Some people have been found to experience allergic reactions
            after consuming products containing E133 and this E number is already banned in Austria,
            Belgium, Denmark, France, Germany, Greece, Italy, Norway, Spain, Sweden and Switzerland.</item>

        <item>E213 – calcium benzoate is a form of preservative that’s used to lengthen the shelf life
            of foods and drinks. It’s often found in low sugar products, but it has been linked to side
            effects in people who have allergic conditions.</item>

        <item>E102 – Tartrazine appears to cause the most allergic and/or intolerance reactions of
            all the azo dyes, particularly amongst those with an aspirin intolerance and asthmatics.
            Other reactions can include migraine, blurred vision, itching, rhinitis and purple skin
            patches, (because of this more use is now being made of Annatto (E160b). In conjunction
            with Benzoic acid (E210) tartrazine appears to create an over-activity in children.</item>

        <item>E122	Carmoisine, Azorubine It appears to cause allergic and/or intolerance reactions,
            particularly amongst those with an aspirin intolerance. Other reactions can include a
            rash similar to nettle rash and water retention. </item>

        <item>E104	Quinoline Yellow used in lipsticks hair products, colognes; also in a wide range
            of medications; may cause dermatitis. Not recommended for consumption by children. Whilst
            being a commonly used colour in the UK its use is banned in Australia, Japan, Norway and
            the United States.</item>

        <item>E107 Yellow 7G It appears to cause allergic and/or intolerance reactions, particularly
            amongst those with an aspirin intolerance and asthma sufferers. Not recommended for
            consumption by children. </item>

        <item>E110 Sunset Yellow Side effects are urticaria (hives), rhinitis (runny nose), nasal
            congestion, allergies, hyperactivity, kidney tumors, chromosomal damage, abdominal pain,
            nausea and vomiting, indigestion, distaste for food; increased incidence of tumors in animals.
            Whilst being a commonly used colour in the UK its use is banned in Norway and Finland.</item>

        <item>E120	Cochineal is an expensive red colouring, not suitable for vegetarians as it is
            extracted from the crushed carcasses of the female Dactylopius coccus, a cactus-feeding
            scale insect, which are killed by either immersion in hot water or by exposure to sunlight,
            steam, or the heat of an oven. The variety in the appearance of commercial cochineal is
            caused by these differing extraction methods. </item>

        <item>E123	Amaranth appears to cause allergic and/or intolerance reactions, similar to nettle
            rash, particularly amongst those with an aspirin intolerance or asthmatics. can provoke asthma,
            eczema and hyperactivity; it caused birth defects and foetal deaths in some animal tests,
            possibly also cancer.Not recommended for consumption by children.
            It is banned in Norway, United States, Russia and Austria (see E129) with a very restricted
            use in France and Italy (caviar only).</item>

        <item>E124	Brilliant Scarlet appears to cause allergic and/or intolerance reactions particularly
            amongst those with an aspirin intolerance or asthmatics. Carcinogen in animals.Not recommended
            for consumption by children.</item>

        <item>E127	Erythrosine  Because food processing at temperatures above 200°c partly degrades
            Erythrosine, releasing iodide, there are fears that it could affect thyroid activity, can
            increase thyroid hormone levels and lead to hyperthyroidism, was shown to cause thyroid cancer
            in rats in a study in 1990. It is toxic to some strains of yeast cells and is also implicated
            in phototoxicity (a sensitivity to light).</item>


        <item>E128	Red 2G: Concerns that it can interfere with blood haemoglobin. Not recommended for
            consumption by children.Britain is the only European Union country to use Red 2G and it
            is also banned in Australia, Austria, Canada, Japan, Norway, Sweden and the United States.</item>

        <item>E131 Patent Blue V: Best avoided by people with allergy reactions as it can cause skin
            sensitivity, a rash similar to nettle rash, itching, nausea, low blood pressure, tremors
            and breathing problems.Not recommended for consumption by children.Banned in Australia, USA and Norway. </item>

        <item>E132	Indigo Carmine, Indigotine, FD and kC Blue 2: used in ice cream, sweets, baked goods,
            confectionery, biscuits.Best avoided by people with allergy reactions as it may cause skin
            sensitivity, a skin rash similar to nettle rash, itching, high blood pressure and
            breathing problems. Not recommended for consumption by children. <b>Banned in Norway</b>.</item>

        <item>E142	Green S: It can be used in mint sauce, desserts, gravy granules, sweets, ice creams, and tinned peas.
            Currently research is ongoing into acceptable intake levels, however it
            is known to cause hyperactivity, asthma, uticaria, and insomnia.Not recommended for
            consumption by children.Banned in Canada, Finland, Japan, Norway, Sweden and the United States.</item>

        <item>E154	Brown FK, Kipper Brown:Found mainly in kippers and smoked mackerel but also
            occasionally in cooked hams and crisps.Not recommended for consumption by children.
            Banned throughout the EU (except in the UK where its use is still permmitted!)
            Also prohibited in Australia, Austria, Canada, Finland, Ireland, Japan, Norway, Sweden
            and the United States. </item>

        <!--Preservatives-->

        <item>E210	Benzoic Acid, Flowers of Benzoin, Phenlycarboxylic Acid and Carboxybenzene:used
            as an antibacterial and antifungal preservative in acid mediums.Can be found in beer, coffee
            essence, dessert sauces, soft drinks, flavouring syrups, fruit juice, pulp and purée, jam
            , margarine, marinated herring and mackerel, pickles, salad cream and dressings, fruit yoghurt,
            baked goods, cheeses, gum, condiments, frozen dairy, relishes, soft sweets, cordials and
            sugar substitutes. Also used in cosmetics. When combined with Tartrazine (E102) it provokes
            a very high hyperactive response in children. Can cause asthma, especially in those dependent
            on steroid asthma medications, is also reputed to cause neurological disorders and to
            react with sulphur bisulphite (E222)</item>

        <item>E212	Potassium Benzoate: Can be found in margarine, pickled cucumbers, pineapple juice
            and table olives. \n People who suffer from asthma, aspirin sensitivity or the skin disease
            urticaria may have allergic reactions and/or find their symptoms become worse following
            consumption of benzoic acid, particularly in combination with tartrazine (E102)</item>

        <item>E214	Ethyl 4-hydroxybenzoate:Preservative found in soft drinks, condiments, baked goods,
            cheese, ice creams, alcoholic drinks, relishes, margarine, salad dressings, medicines and
            other products.<b>Not recommended for consumption by children.</b>\nNot permitted for use in France and Australia. </item>

        <item>E215	Sodium ethyl 4-hydroxybenzoate: It is used as an antifungal preservative.Not recommended
            for consumption by children.\nNot permitted for use in France or Australia.</item>

        <item>E216	Propyl 4-hydroxybenzoate: It is a preservative typically found in many water-based
            cosmetics, such as creams, lotions, shampoos and bath products. As a food additive, it
            has the E number E216. Not recomended for consumption by children. Possible contact allergen.
            \nNot permitted for use in France or Australia.</item>

        <item>E217	Sodium propyl 4-hydroxybenzoate: Preservative. \nNot recommended for consumption
                    by children. Not permitted for use in France or Australia.</item>

        <item>E218	Methyl 4-hydroxybenzoate:Preservative.\nCan cause allergic reactions, particularly
            to the skin.Not recommended to be consumed by children.\nNot permitted for use in France or Australia.</item>

        <item>E219	Sodium methyl 4-hydroxybenzoate:Not recommended to be consumed by children.
            The Hyperactive Childrens Support Group belive that a link exists between this additive
            and hyperactive behavioural disorders in children. \nNot permitted for use in France or Australia.</item>

        <item>E220	Sulphur Dioxide: known to provoke asthma attacks and is difficult to metabolise
            for those with impaired kidney function. It also <u>destroys</u> vitamins B1 and E.\nTypically found
            in beers, soft drinks, dried fruit, juices, cordials, wine, vinegar, and potato products.
            \nNot recommended for consumption by children. </item>

        <item>E221	Sodium Sulphite: used as a decontaminating agent in fresh orange juice, and during
            sugar refining.May trigger asthma, and <u>destroys</u> vitamins B1 and E.\nNot recommended
            for consumption by children.</item>

        <item>E222	Sodium hydrogen sulphite, Sodium bisulphite:preservative.May cause an allergic
            reaction in some people, especially asthmatics.<b>Destroys vitamins B1 and E.</b>\nNot
            recommended for consumption by children. </item>
        <item>E223	Sodium Metabisulphite: May cause allergic reactions, particularly skin irritation,
            gastric irritation and asthma.\nNot recommended for consumption by children.</item>

        <item>E224	Potassium Metabisulphite: Can cause asthma, cyanosis, faintness and even
            unconsciousness.\nNot recommended to be consumed by children.</item>

        <item>E226	Calcium Sulphite: May cause asthma. A gastric irritant.<u>Destroys vitamins B and E.</u>\n
            Not recommended for consumption by children.<b>Not permitted in Australia.</b></item>

        <item>E227	Calcium Hydrogen Sulphite: May cause allergic reaction. \nNot recommended for
            consumption by children.\nNot permitted in australia.</item>

        <item>E230	Biphenyl: It is excreted unaltered by the kidneys. Sensitivity has been reported for people handling
            large consignments of citrus fruits (ships, trucks).\nUsed for agricultural purposes
            (an aromatic fungicide), it is a skin and eye irritant.\nBiphenyl is a constituent of the
            wood preservative creosote.\nNot recommended for consumption by children.</item>

        <item>E231	Orthophenylphenol, 2-hydroxybiphenyl:  this preservative remains on the skins of
            fruits when they arrive at the retailer.Not recommended for consumption by children.Not
            permitted in Australia.</item>

        <item>E232	Sodium orthophenylphenol: Not recommended for consumption by children.\nNot permitted
            in Australia.</item>

        <item>E233	Thiabendazole, 2-(Thiazol-4-yl) benzimidazole: Banned in some countries, it is
            typically applied to citrus fruits, apples, pears, potatoes, bananas, mushrooms, meat,
            and milk .</item>

        <item>E239	Hexamethylenetetramine: used as a preservative against fungi in food products such
            as Caviar, cheese, herring and preserved fish.
        \nAmongst many others, this substance is utilised as a cross-linking agent for resins,
            rubber-to-textile adhesive, protein modifier, organic synthesis, pharmaceuticals, an
            ingredient for explosives, fuel tablets, rubber accelerator, fungicide, corrosion inhibitor,
            shrink proofing textiles and as an anti-bacterial agent</item>

        <item>E249	Potassium nitrite: It is a potential carcinogen, and is prohibited in foods for
            infants and young children.
            </item>


        <item>E250	Sodium nitrite: Health effects are acute methemoglobinemia (haemoglobin loses its
            ability to carry oxygen). Early symptoms include irritability, lack of energy, headache,
            dizziness, vomiting, diaorrhea, laboured breathing and a blue-gray or pale purple colouration
            to areas around the eyes, mouth, lips, hands and feet (blue baby syndrome).\nIn severe
            untreated cases, brain damage and eventually death can result from suffocation due to lack
            of oxygen. Pregnant women and infants below 3 months should stay away from nitrites.
            Individuals with digestive difficulties due to reduced stomach acidity are also at higher risk.
            \nJoint FAO/WHO Expert Committee on Food Additives has established an ADI of 0-0.06mg/kg bw.
            U.S. Department of Agriculture has the specifications that sodium nitrite content should not
            exceed 200ppm in finished products. Use of Sodium nitrite is banned in Norway, Sweden, Canada,
            Germany.</item>

        <item>E251	Sodium nitrate: Sodium nitrate is a salt used extensively as a preservative and
            colour fixative of processed meats such as sausage and bacon. It is coded as E251 by European Union.
            \nNitrates by themselves are non-toxic but when added to meat break down into nitrite.
            The nitrite then reacts with protein to produce N-nitroso compounds which is carcinogenic
            in test animals, evidence is inconclusive regarding their potential to cause cancer
            (such as stomach cancer) in humans.</item>

        <item>E252	Potassium nitrate: prolonged exposure to even small quantities may cause anaemia
            or kidney inflammation, with ingestion of large amounts possibly causing severe abdominal
            pain and vomiting, muscular weakness, vertigo and irregular pulse.</item>
        <item>EXXX	XXXXXXXXXXX</item>


        <!-- http://www.ukfoodguide.net/bestavoided.htm -->


    </string-array>

    <string-array name="headingForBadENumbersArray">

        <!-- this heading arrays should represent qoloquial name for e-number, there should be the
         same number of items in this array as in the one above (badENumbersCardArray) -->
        <item>E129 Allura Red AC</item>
        <item>E621 – monosodium glutamate</item>
        <item>E951 – aspartame</item>
        <item>E211 – sodium benzoate</item>
        <item>E150d Sulphite-ammonia caramel</item>
        <item>E150c Ammonia caramel</item>
        <item>E151 – brilliant black BN</item>
        <item>E133 – brilliant blue FCF</item>
        <item>E213 – calcium benzoate</item>
        <item>E102 – tartrazine</item>
        <item>E122	Carmoisine, Azorubine</item>
        <item>E104	Quinoline Yellow</item>
        <item>E107 Yellow 7G</item>
        <item>E110	Sunset Yellow</item>
        <item>E120	Cochineal0</item>
        <item>E123	Amaranth</item>
        <item>E124	Brilliant Scarlet</item>
        <item>E127	Erythrosine</item>
        <item>E128	Red 2G</item>
        <item>E131 Patent Blue V</item>
        <item>E132	Indigo Carmine</item>
        <item>E142	Green S</item>
        <item>E154	Brown FK</item>
        <item>E210	Benzoic Acid</item>
        <item>E212	Potassium Benzoate</item>

        <item>E214	Ethyl 4-hydroxybenzoate</item>
        <item>E215	Sodium ethyl 4-hydroxybenzoate</item>

        <item>E216	Propyl 4-hydroxybenzoate</item>

        <item>E217	Sodium propyl 4-hydroxybenzoate</item>

        <item>E218	Methyl 4-hydroxybenzoate</item>

        <item>E219	Sodium methyl 4-hydroxybenzoate</item>
        <item>E220	Sulphur Dioxide</item>

        <item>E221	Sodium Sulphite</item>
        <item>E222	Sodium hydrogen sulphite</item>

        <item>E223	Sodium Metabisulphite</item>
        <item>E224	Potassium Metabisulphite</item>
        <item>E226	Calcium Sulphite</item>
        <item>E227	Calcium Hydrogen Sulphite</item>
        <item>E230	Biphenyl</item>
        <item>E231	Orthophenylphenol</item>
        <item>E232	Sodium orthophenylpheno</item>
        <item>E233	Thiabendazole</item>
        <item>E239	Hexamethylenetetramine</item>
        <item>E249	Potassium nitrite</item>
        <item>E250	Sodium nitrite</item>
        <item>E251	Sodium nitrate</item>
        <item>E252	Potassium nitrate</item>
        <item>EXXX	XXXXXXXXXXX</item>
        <item>EXXX	XXXXXXXXXXX</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="test">test  tastatst attsatsa test  tastatst attsatsa test  tastatst attsatsa</string>
</resources>